<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eightbitraptor</title>
    <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on eightbitraptor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:30:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eightbitraptor.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GC in Ruby: Part 2 (a), What is GC, Mark &amp; Sweep, and how Ruby marks objects</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/04/15/gc-in-ruby-part-2-a-what-is-gc-mark-sweep-and-how-ruby-marks-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:30:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/04/15/gc-in-ruby-part-2-a-what-is-gc-mark-sweep-and-how-ruby-marks-objects/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that a huge proportion of the folks reading this post are programming with languages that implement automatic dynamic memory management. Ruby, Python, Go, JavaScript, Haskell, Swift, Lisp, Dart, and of course anything based on the .NET CLR or the JVM are all languages that manage memory automatically.
It&amp;rsquo;s highly likely that, if you&amp;rsquo;ve never had to explicitly call malloc or a related API, then you&amp;rsquo;re working in a language with automatic dynamic memory management1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GC in Ruby: Part 1, An overview of memory layout</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/23/gc-in-ruby-part-1-an-overview-of-memory-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 22:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/23/gc-in-ruby-part-1-an-overview-of-memory-layout/</guid>
      <description>An introduction and code walkthrough of the Ruby memory model</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 2021.09: Elaborately carved metals</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/08/weeknote-2021.09-elaborately-carved-metals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 13:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/08/weeknote-2021.09-elaborately-carved-metals/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to a lot of music this week. Rediscovered an old favourite of mine: Cult of Luna. I had no idea they were still making music, I used to listen to these guys in my first year of Uni. Turns out their latest album is an absolute banger.
  A friend and work colleague switched to Vim recently, and asked me for some advice on learning it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 2021.08: Sweat the small stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/01/weeknote-2021.08-sweat-the-small-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 13:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/03/01/weeknote-2021.08-sweat-the-small-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Not much to report again this week. Still waiting on keyboard PCB&amp;rsquo;s so no change on that front.
  Did knock up a quick 3d print case design loosely based on the old IBM F62 Kishsaver design. haven&amp;rsquo;t finished printing and assembling it yet so no pics for now; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to ruin the surprise.
  After a bit of an abortive start last time. I started to run again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 2021.07: Buy one, get one free</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/21/weeknote-2021.07-buy-one-get-one-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 20:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/21/weeknote-2021.07-buy-one-get-one-free/</guid>
      <description>Well. That&amp;rsquo;s it! Missed a week. Had to happen sooner or later. It&amp;rsquo;s like scratching a new laptop. After carefully protecting the innocence of a pristine new thing, the first ding has been made and it&amp;rsquo;s all downhill from here!
Flippancy aside, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and maintain a regular cadence with these weeknotes. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed writing them, the reflection has been useful and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to reading back on them in a years time so see where I am and where I&amp;rsquo;ve come from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.05: The white death is falling</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/10/weeknotes-2021.05-the-white-death-is-falling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 13:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/10/weeknotes-2021.05-the-white-death-is-falling/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s snowing. Actually snowing, like settling on the ground and making everything white. This almost never happens here and I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. It&amp;rsquo;s icy and cold and makes driving anywhere really stressful.
At least I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to drive anywhere because Pandemic.
I mainly don&amp;rsquo;t like the snow because I have the balance of a drunk gnat glued to a housebrick. I fall over almost every time it gets remotely icy or snows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.04: Upright through the grace of caffeine</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/01/weeknotes-2021.04-upright-through-the-grace-of-caffeine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/02/01/weeknotes-2021.04-upright-through-the-grace-of-caffeine/</guid>
      <description>4 weeks in and I broke my self-imposed rule of publishing weeknotes by Sunday night. But that&amp;rsquo;s OK because fuck all happened this week anyway, just busywork and stress. No progress on keyboard - although some very nice chap from one of the Discord servers I&amp;rsquo;m in sent me a couple of ai03&amp;rsquo;s unified daughterboards which I&amp;rsquo;m keen to play with. Having them means that I no longer need to really think about how to wire up a USB-C port correctly, and that I am far less restricted about where to position the port in the case than I would be if it was directly attached to the PCB, so that&amp;rsquo;s exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.03: Short</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/24/weeknotes-2021.03-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 22:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/24/weeknotes-2021.03-short/</guid>
      <description>At some point this week Phoebe wanted to watch videos of Volcanos and Thunderstorms. We sat down together to try and find some videos. We watched a lot of educational content which was fun - but then got utterly side-tracked with this 30 day timelapse from the roof of a container ship. She was just as hooked as me! I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this a bunch of times since then and it may just be the most captivating 10 minutes of YouTube I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.02: Vaguely sketchy</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/16/weeknotes-2021.02-vaguely-sketchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/16/weeknotes-2021.02-vaguely-sketchy/</guid>
      <description>I failed to take many notes this week so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be doing this from memory. Honestly not a ringing endorsement of my ability to keep up this weeknotes thing, but at least this post made it onto the internet on time so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s enough for now?
  I&amp;rsquo;m still in touch with the lovely man at the running shop. He watched my video, assessed that I do something called overpronating and then dropped round 3 pairs of shoes which I&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing around the house for the last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.01: Slacks Dead Jim</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/07/weeknotes-2021.01-slacks-dead-jim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 07:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/07/weeknotes-2021.01-slacks-dead-jim/</guid>
      <description>First day back to work after a couple of weeks off and Slack dies as soon as the East coast wakes up. Amazing how debilitating it now feels when slack starts having issues, it&amp;rsquo;s like a lifeline has just been cut off. I swear it never used to feel this bad. Elliot had his first round of vaccinations this week. He&amp;rsquo;s absolutely miserable - which I guess is what happens when someone jabs needles in both legs filled with a rotovirus/meningitis cocktail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.00: Late to the party</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/04/weeknotes-2021.00-late-to-the-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/04/weeknotes-2021.00-late-to-the-party/</guid>
      <description>I am jumping on the weeknotes bandwagon. I&amp;rsquo;m in good company, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by good people, particularly Tom, Chris, and Paul. Done a lot of walking so far in 2021, we&amp;rsquo;ve been out walking along the beach at Hythe, and spent multiple trips to Leeds Castle. Leeds castle is our lifeline at the moment during lockdown winter - somewhere that&amp;rsquo;s accessible with a pram, easy to keep yourself distant from other people, fun for the kids, but also has toilets, baby changing facilities and somewhere to get coffee and food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020: A Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/03/2020-a-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 22:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/03/2020-a-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I’ve not written a post like this before but 2020 has been a year of firsts so let’s give it a go.
I’m not sure what I achieved last year. I imagine a lot of people right now are feeling pretty similar: that 2020 was simultaneously the longest and the shortest year we’ve ever experienced. But I shall summarise mine, and we’ll see where we get.
January and February started on a reasonably positive note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2020.30: Tea towels are flammable</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/07/26/weeknotes-2020.30-tea-towels-are-flammable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 13:18:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/07/26/weeknotes-2020.30-tea-towels-are-flammable/</guid>
      <description>My monitor went bang last week, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my laptop screen propped up on a pile of books. Work arranged for me to have a new monitor which arrived on Tuesday. They sent me an upgrade - it&amp;rsquo;s a couple of inches bigger than my old screen and 4k rather than 2k. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely lovely, probably partly due to how grateful my eyes are to not be peering over my desk at a laptop screen any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A typing journey, part 2: Down the rabbit hole</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/03/11/a-typing-journey-part-2-down-the-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 08:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/03/11/a-typing-journey-part-2-down-the-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>In my last post about mechanical keyboards, I was getting ready to dip my toe into the weird and wonderful world of custom ergonomic keyboards. Young and full of naïvete I hadn&amp;rsquo;t fully grasped the depth of the hobby I was about to pick up, nor quite how tight it would grab me!
Fast forward a few months, and in addition to owning and using my bamboo Redox every day, I&amp;rsquo;ve also:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A typing journey, part 1: My first Keyboard®</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/10/14/a-typing-journey-part-1-my-first-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 07:51:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/10/14/a-typing-journey-part-1-my-first-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some recurring pains in my back and arms. The forearms, wrists and thumbs particularly, most often noticeable on my left side. It gets bad enough sometimes that it can prevent me from typing, or certainly be painful enough to be distracting when I am trying to work.
It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I started working from home, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really evaluated the suitability of my workspace for prolonged use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats in My Bag: Coffee Shop Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/09/25/whats-in-my-bag-coffee-shop-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 12:08:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/09/25/whats-in-my-bag-coffee-shop-edition/</guid>
      <description>The Every Day Carry (EDC) community is an internet subculture that seems to have originated with firearms enthusiasts in the USA and has slowly been spreading out to the rest of the internet. There&amp;rsquo;s a dedicated subreddit, a lifestyle blog, and Vox have even written articles about it.
The basic premise is to think, reflect and iterate on the items that people carry in their pockets, handbags or rucksacks to optimise them for the tasks which will occupy most of the day; often with an alternative motive of showing off the shiny things in the most photogenic way possible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2018/12/17/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2018/12/17/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally started my first personal site and blog in 2009 on the
now defunct domain &lt;code&gt;theshadowaspect.com&lt;/code&gt;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to
decide that I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of the name and so in January 2010 I
registered &lt;code&gt;eightbitraptor.com&lt;/code&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;ve been ever since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Matt. I was born in the early 80&amp;rsquo;s in Margate, a seaside town in the county of Kent in the UK. Currently I live in Sevenoaks; still in Kent, but closer to London; with my wife, daughter and our cat.
I hold a BEng (hons) in Computer Systems Engineering from the University of Kent.
I also hold a MSc in Broadband and Mobile Communication Networks from the same University after my undergraduate supervisor applied for EPSRC funding on my behalf (and without my knowledge, it was a pleasant surprise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with headless VirtualBox VM&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2016/07/08/working-with-headless-virtualbox-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2016/07/08/working-with-headless-virtualbox-vms/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time using both OSX and Linux. Personally I tend to prefer using Linux, however my work have provided me with a MacBook Pro and in order to make working with my colleagues as pain free as possible, I use OSX on it.
I still like to do a lot of work that relies on being on Linux however, and there are a bunch of ways to acheive this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emacs startup process: Init files</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2014/07/21/the-emacs-startup-process-init-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2014/07/21/the-emacs-startup-process-init-files/</guid>
      <description>I started thinking about this when I arranged a short remote pairing session to help a friend work through some pain he was having with his Emacs configuration. The session hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet but it got me interested enough in what Emacs does under the hood when it starts up, particularly when it loads your config and I though it might make an interesting blog post.
The .emacs file. When Emacs starts up it loads your configuration from a file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
