<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eightbitraptor</title>
    <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on eightbitraptor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:53:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eightbitraptor.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2021.00: Late to the party</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/04/weeknotes-2021.00-late-to-the-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/04/weeknotes-2021.00-late-to-the-party/</guid>
      <description>I am jumping on the weeknotes bandwagon. I&amp;rsquo;m in good company, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by good people, particularly Tom, Chris, and Paul. Done a lot of walking so far in 2021, we&amp;rsquo;ve been out walking along the beach at Hythe, and spent multiple trips to Leeds Castle. Leeds castle is our lifeline at the moment during lockdown winter - somewhere that&amp;rsquo;s accessible with a pram, easy to keep yourself distant from other people, fun for the kids, but also has toilets, baby changing facilities and somewhere to get coffee and food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020: A Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/03/2020-a-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 22:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2021/01/03/2020-a-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I’ve not written a post like this before but 2020 has been a year of firsts so let’s give it a go.
I’m not sure what I achieved last year. I imagine a lot of people right now are feeling pretty similar: that 2020 was simultaneously the longest and the shortest year we’ve ever experienced. But I shall summarise mine, and we’ll see where we get.
January and February started on a reasonably positive note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 2020.30: Tea towels are flammable</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/07/26/weeknotes-2020.30-tea-towels-are-flammable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 13:18:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/07/26/weeknotes-2020.30-tea-towels-are-flammable/</guid>
      <description>My monitor went bang last week, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my laptop screen propped up on a pile of books. Work arranged for me to have a new monitor which arrived on Tuesday. They sent me an upgrade - it&amp;rsquo;s a couple of inches bigger than my old screen and 4k rather than 2k. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely lovely, probably partly due to how grateful my eyes are to not be peering over my desk at a laptop screen any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A typing journey, part 2: Down the rabbit hole</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/03/11/a-typing-journey-part-2-down-the-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 08:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2020/03/11/a-typing-journey-part-2-down-the-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>In my last post about mechanical keyboards, I was getting ready to dip my toe into the weird and wonderful world of custom ergonomic keyboards. Young and full of naïvete I hadn&amp;rsquo;t fully grasped the depth of the hobby I was about to pick up, nor quite how tight it would grab me!
Fast forward a few months, and in addition to owning and using my bamboo Redox every day, I&amp;rsquo;ve also:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A typing journey, part 1: My first Keyboard®</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/10/14/a-typing-journey-part-1-my-first-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 07:51:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/10/14/a-typing-journey-part-1-my-first-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some recurring pains in my back and arms. The forearms, wrists and thumbs particularly, most often noticeable on my left side. It gets bad enough sometimes that it can prevent me from typing, or certainly be painful enough to be distracting when I am trying to work.
It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I started working from home, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really evaluated the suitability of my workspace for prolonged use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats in My Bag: Coffee Shop Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/09/25/whats-in-my-bag-coffee-shop-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 12:08:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2019/09/25/whats-in-my-bag-coffee-shop-edition/</guid>
      <description>The Every Day Carry (EDC) community is an internet subculture that seems to have originated with firearms enthusiasts in the USA and has slowly been spreading out to the rest of the internet. There&amp;rsquo;s a dedicated subreddit, a lifestyle blog, and Vox have even written articles about it.
The basic premise is to think, reflect and iterate on the items that people carry in their pockets, handbags or rucksacks to optimise them for the tasks which will occupy most of the day; often with an alternative motive of showing off the shiny things in the most photogenic way possible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2018/12/17/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2018/12/17/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally started my first personal site and blog in 2009 on the
now defunct domain &lt;code&gt;theshadowaspect.com&lt;/code&gt;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to
decide that I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of the name and so in January 2010 I
registered &lt;code&gt;eightbitraptor.com&lt;/code&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;ve been ever since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Matt. I was born in the early 80&amp;rsquo;s in Margate, a seaside town in the county of Kent in the UK. Currently I live in Sevenoaks; still in Kent, but closer to London; with my wife, daughter and our cat.
I hold a BEng (hons) in Computer Systems Engineering from the University of Kent.
I also hold a MSc in Broadband and Mobile Communication Networks from the same University after my undergraduate supervisor applied for EPSRC funding on my behalf (and without my knowledge, it was a pleasant surprise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with headless VirtualBox VM&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2016/07/08/working-with-headless-virtualbox-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2016/07/08/working-with-headless-virtualbox-vms/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time using both OSX and Linux. Personally I tend to prefer using Linux, however my work have provided me with a MacBook Pro and in order to make working with my colleagues as pain free as possible, I use OSX on it.
I still like to do a lot of work that relies on being on Linux however, and there are a bunch of ways to acheive this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emacs startup process: Init files</title>
      <link>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2014/07/21/the-emacs-startup-process-init-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eightbitraptor.com/2014/07/21/the-emacs-startup-process-init-files/</guid>
      <description>I started thinking about this when I arranged a short remote pairing session to help a friend work through some pain he was having with his Emacs configuration. The session hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet but it got me interested enough in what Emacs does under the hood when it starts up, particularly when it loads your config and I though it might make an interesting blog post.
The .emacs file. When Emacs starts up it loads your configuration from a file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
